## **Victor Baker**

## mail@victorbaker.dev

Portfolio: victorbaker.dev | LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/baker-v | GitHub: github.com/bakerv

Passionate about solving problems and implementing solutions. Experienced with conveying technical information to all levels, influencing decisions, and developing customer relationships. Strong background in vector calculus, differential equations, and linear algebra. Always on the lookout for opportunities to learn and improve.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Programming Languages:** Python, JavaScript, SQL, NoSQL, Excel VBA, MATLAB, Java, C# **Technologies:** NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Scikit-learn, TensorFlow, Tableau, MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, Leaflet.js, Plotly.js, D3.js, OpenCV, Aiortc, Flask, Jupyter Notebooks

#### **PROJECTS**

## Facial Emotion Recognition | github.com/bakerv/fer-webcam

This app receives a video stream from the user's browser, and returns an emotion prediction. Face detection is accomplished using a Haar Cascade classifier and a Convolutional Neural Network is used for emotion prediction.

- Role: Team Lead
- Tools: Python, JavaScript, TensorFlow, OpenCV, WebRTC, Aiortc, Aiohttp and others

## Citi Bike Data Pipeline | github.com/bakerv/citibike-data-extraction 2013-2021

Extracting monthly trip data from AWS S3 buckets, and loading it into a SQL Database. The 112 million trips are aggregated to create a Tableau dashboard on bicycle longevity.

- Role: Sole author
- Tools Used: Python, SQL, Tableau, Pandas, SQLAlchemy, Python IO, ZipFile, AWS

## **Shark Sighting API** | github.com/bakerv/sharks-western-australia

GeoJSON data from the Government of Western Australia's API is used in an interactive map. The raw data from the API is cleaned, and then added to a leaflet map as a custom icon for eack shark species or ship.

- Role: Team Member
- Tools Used: Python, JavaScript, SQL, HTML/CSS, Pandas, Leaflet.js, D3.js and others

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Horticulturist / Estate Gardener**

June 2019 – August 2021 San Antonio, TX

**Private Estate** 

- Created visual tools to facilitate communication of technical information
- Developed vendor network and implemented ordering procedures for the property
- Performed analysis and problem solving for critical systems

## Assistant Greengoods Manager / Perennial Department Head

January 2014 – May 2019 San Antonio, TX

Rainbow Gardens #3

- Created and implemented the Integrated Pest Management program
- Ensured return on investment through sourcing, ordering, and inventory management
- Excellent customer reviews while functioning as the customer service lead

# The University of Texas at San Antonio

Jan 2010 - June 2010 Undergraduate Research Assistant – Data Visualization San Antonio, TX Advisor: Kay Robbins, Ph.D.

- Developed tools with MATLAB to measure synchronization in nonlinear systems.
- Visualized neurological EEG data from human subjects.

## **EDUCATION**

# **Certificate, Data Analytics**

The University of Texas at San Antonio San Antonio, TX

# **Bachelor of Science, Physics**

The University of Texas at San Antonio San Antonio, TX